Contact

www.linkedin.com/in/rui-martins-50134852 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

IFRS

External Audit
Internal Controls

Languages

Portuguese

English

Spanish

Certifications

Revisor Oficial de Contas

EY Strategic Leadership for Partners Program (2022)

Perito Contabilista

Rui Martins

Partner, Assurance Leader

Lisboa, Lisbon, Portugal

Summary

Highly driven Assurance professional, with 27 years of experience in EY, 17 of which as a partner.

Extensive experience in Portugal and Angola, where he is responsible for the external audit of large and complex clients, both of local and multinational companies, including the coordination of international engagements for Portuguese clients with an international footprint.

Expert in the Retail, Utilities and Oil&Gas industries, having worked with some of the largest companies present in the Portuguese and Angolan markets. His portfolio of clients results in an extensive experience in financial reporting under IFRS and US GAAP, as well as in the audit of SAP-based financial reporting.

Analytics and Audit Transformation lead Partner for EY in Portugal, having also the responsibility for Training and Audit Quality Control in Portugal.

Chartered Accountant (Revisor Oficial de Contas) in Portugal, since 2001, and a Perito Contabilista in Angola since 2012.

Experience

EY

31 years 8 months

Partner, Assurance

July 2004 - Present (20 years 10 months)

Portugal and Angola

Responsible for a portfolio of audit clients, including middle-market and large accounts, both in Portugal and Angola. Leader of a team of more than 100 auditors, with ultimate responsibility in the sign-off of the financial statements of companies reporting in local, IFRS and US-GAAP accounting standards.

Junior - Manager September 1993 - June 2004 (10 years 10 months) Portugal and Angola

Progressive responsibilities from team member to team leader of progressively larger audit engagements, while undergoing extensive technical training, both in Portugal and abroad.

Education

Instituto Superior de Economia e Gestão
Bachelor's degree, Management, specializing in Finance · (1988 - 1993)